Peter Wardle

Software / Platform Engineer (+44)07590551845 / peter@peterwardle.co.uk

ABOUT

I am an ambitious Software and Platform Engineer with over 10 years experience, who takes great pride in producing work to a high standard. I currently hold the position of Lead Site Reliability Engineer at Bede Gaming, a supplier of software to the online gambling and social gaming industries.

My aim throughout my career is to be constantly improving and expanding my skills, knowledge and experience, and welcome the opportunity to do so.

Other than development, my day-to-day responsibilities can range from project planning and management, ensuring platform availability and stability, along with supporting other members of the engineering/platform team.

Outside of work I regularly attend local user groups; GolangNE and PHPNE.

SKILLS

ENGINEERING

- ▶ Bash/Shell
- Docker/Docker-Compose
- Git (Version Control)
- ► Go
- Kubernetes (inc. AKS, Helm)
- MySQL
- PHP (Lumen, Laravel)
- Python

SUPPORTING

- Coaching and supporting team members
- Project planning
- Project management
- Server management/monitoring

WORK EXPERIENCE

Lead Site Reliability Engineer
Bede Gaming - Aug 2021 to Present

Following 3 years in an SRE role at Bede Gaming the opportunity arose to wider impact on the Fabric (SRE) team within Bede. This offered the chance to support more of the coaching of other SREs as well as expanding and developing my supporting skills along-side more technical skills.

Since taking the Lead role for the team we took on two new SREs - one of whom was completely new to this type of role, requiring more focussed support and as such worked on a personal development plan together to better support their progression in this the role.

The primary project for the team while in the role has been the migration of our IaC over to a CI/CD process to reduce the team resources and time required to apply our IaC changes across all Bede's clients/environments. Currently being in the staggered on-boarding phase.

Alongside the team specific duties as part of this change in role - I've also taking on a more supporting role across the wider Fabric tribe to offer guidance and support to SREs across all teams - to aid in the development of solutions, as well as more technical coaching on more niche areas of Bede's infrastructure specifically or specific technologies.

Site Reliability Engineer Bede Gaming - May 2018 to Aug 2021

Looking for a chance to further develop and make use of experience gained developing and supporting a Kubernetes platform in my previous role, I decided to take up an SRE role at Bede Gaming.

With ambitious plans for migrating their gambling and social gaming platform to containers and leveraging automated orchestration tooling, such as Kubernetes, this seemed like the perfect opportunity.

During my time in this role the most noteworthy projects I've been involved in have been:

 Network security improvements via the introduction of NVAs and subnet restrictions via Azure NSGs limiting traffic for internal platform communications, wider Bede networks and external network communications.

- Network design to support integration with a client's on-premise network with a reduced network range to avoid conflicting/overlapping network ranges between Bede and Client via Azure's Express Route offering.
- Design, planning and implementation of a Kubernetes (via AKS) hosting platform for Bede's service offering - that would enable a phased transition from VMs > Hybrid > Full-Kubernetes hosting of all software components.

Principal Platform Engineer EvaluAgent / SocialRel8 - Jul 2016 to May 2018

After deciding to move away from an agency role to focus on platform-based engineering and support, I became a Principal Platform Engineer at EvaluAgent, where I provided platform and architectural direction for their multi-channel, quality monitoring platform for call centres.

One purpose of my role was to integrate their legacy system to the current platform using APIs, SSO and migration tasks through standardised JSON messages via SQS and worker processes.

The main focus of my role was to deliver the company's products/solutions as disparate services; comprising of RESTful APIs based upon the JSON API specification, to support client-side web applications. Each service ran within a Docker container, built and tested by our automated CI tool (Jenkins) and stored within AWS ECR. This allowed us to deploy multiple, isolated, versions on Kubernetes clusters hosted on AWS, created via Kops, using Helm for each client/contract - allowing full separation of client systems.

As Principal Platform Engineer, I also held additional leadership responsibilities including:

- Coaching and supporting all members of the engineering team.
- · Creation of tools to aid team processes, allowing easier completion of tasks.
- Use Make to give each project/service a standardised way for both engineers and our CI tool (Jenkins) to complete common tasks without the need to understand the underlying processes and systems.
- Representing the wider engineering team at senior-level company meetings.
- Managing platform operations including monitoring, metrics and analytics.

Technical Director / Digital Team Lead
Drummond Central - Feb 2013 to Jul 2016

At Drummond Central, I managed a number of web-based projects for recognisable brands including; Nexus, Saks Hair & Beauty, Tor Coatings, NCFE, Omega PLC, Osbit Power, NewcastleGatesheadInitiative (Geordieland) and Newcastle City Council.

As Technical Director, I was responsible for the overall direction of all digital output within the agency. This included; technical strategy, development, execution and innovation, as well as overseeing all development for their in-house, API-based, CMS platform.

Responsibilities included:

- Managing and maintaining infrastructure and making architectural decisions to improve internal functions.
- Overseeing all client projects, ensuring they remain within scope and budget.
- Quality assurance on all internal and external projects.
- Product road mapping and optimising their in-house CMS platform.
- Ensuring coding standards are enforced amongst the full digital team.
- Providing company-wide technical advice and support, not just within the digital team.
- Managing, training, motivating and developing all teams across the company.

Previous to my Technical Director role, I was Digital Team Lead where I managed the production and maintenance of websites and applications for both clients and internal products/systems.

Overall duties, outside of those listed above, were:

- Leading the digital team and overseeing/managing the overall output and quality of work for both backend and frontend.
- Regularly attending client meetings to update the status on ongoing projects and to discuss technical requirements.
- Responsibility for choosing software and solutions for all client projects.

Web Development Team Lead / Senior Developer Moko Digital / Riff Raff / Dene - Oct 2009 to Jan 2013

After starting Riff Raff as a Middle-weight Developer, I took over the lead of a project within my first month, where my role was to manage the creation of a user interface for an undocumented service handling flight bookings. I was required to communicate with both the client and the service provider to determine project requirements and facilitate a successful implementation.

Alongside this, I also tried to continually advance and improve the company's platform and development process. This included, but was not limited to; switching the manual deployment process to an automated solution using Capistrano, which allowed us to have a much easier and safer deploy/release process for other members of the team.

As well as my usual development duties, other day-to-day responsibilities as part of this role included:

- Project planning
- · Client and project management
- Server administration
- Training and support new and existing members of the team

Web Developer

PointOv / Ethical Superstore Ltd - April 2009 to Oct 2009

I started this job as part of a new development team. Within the first few weeks, I had to become accustomed to company systems with little to no guidance, ready to start a major project that needed to be completed to an incredibly strict deadline. This was to create a new eCommerce system based on the company's own eCommerce site, where it would need to retrieve stock information for its products from the, already existing, system.

Having only a few weeks to understand how the current system functioned, I liaised with senior members of the warehouse and product teams to get an understanding of how they used the current system so that the proposed solution would meet the needs of all stakeholders involved.

In order to complete this project successfully, it was apparent we also had to find a more efficient way to manage stock. To achieve this, I developed a centralised stock management system that used XML payloads to push updates out to all systems via the use of a simple API component employed on each of the respective systems.

This allowed greater control over what and how stock was manipulated, easier maintenance of the logic behind the stock for different types of products (as this was now held in one central location, and stock data to be updated in real-time, unlike the previous system which only kept stock information updated to the nearest hour.

Web Developer / Technical Support MITAC Partnership Ltd - August 2005 to April 2009

Starting as a placement year within University, I was given the chance to continue as a full-time employee after graduating, due to my strong work ethic and ability to complete work to a high standard.

The biggest project I worked on was an application system for students applying to colleges, sixth forms and work-based learning providers. This had two sides to it; building the student application that allowed them to apply to different providers and an admin

application which allowed the education providers to track and respond to applications and monitor student progress whilst out on placement.

- · XHTML, CSS and Javascript frontend.
- Database driven backend developed using PHP and MySQL.
- Development to OWASP Top 10 security standards for web applications.
- Data transfer in XML and Excel format.

Developing this system also allowed me to take on an additional technical support role where I offered direct user guidance and support to resolve system issues that the education providers found via telephone support. This afforded me the opportunity to greater understand how the system was used so that I was able to improve the system process through increased user experience or features that made the education provider's process smoother.

QUALIFICATIONS

BSc Internet Computing (Hons) Degree University of Northumbria at Newcastle - September 2003 to July 2007

This was a three-year degree with an additional placement year, which I took at MITAC Partnership Ltd. I achieved a 2:1 and some of the modules I completed were:

- Information Security
- Application Integration Technologies (Java & XML)
- Web Database Systems (PHP, XML & MySQL)
- Relational Databases (SQL)
- Object-Oriented Design (UML)

CONFERENCES

Scale Summit, London, 2018

A one-day "unconference", that I will be attending in 2018, it's a different take on the typical conference structure, with no pre-planned talks it is driven by the attendees and their interests and experiences.

dotGo, Paris, 2017

A one-day conference, with talks covering various best-practices for developing Go tools and services. The standout talk, for me personally, was from Sameer Ajmani, Simulating a

real-world system in Go, which was a fantastic overview on modelling/architecting systems and the compromise between concurrent and sequential processes and systems.

FOSDEM, Brussels, 2016

A two-day conference covering a vast array of topics; from languages, tools and operating systems. My topics of particular focus were; containerisation (Docker, Kubernetes) and Go.

Golang UK, London, 2015

This was the inaugural Golang UK conference and my first foray into Go development. After attending this conference I released my first production Go service which created a WebSocket server that would relay messages received from an AMQP exchange (Rabbit-MQ) and send on to all connected clients over the WebSocket protocol.

PHPBenelux, Antwerp, 2015

A two-day conference, with talks covering various practices and tools related to PHP development specifically but some also relevant to development in general.

PHPNE, Newcastle, 2014

A one-day conference, that I was involved in planning and organising, as well as giving the closing remarks to the attendees to bring a close to the day-long conference. It was a 3-track conference covering topics specific to PHP development, server operations and war-stories (lessons learnt the hard way).

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

I try to run regularly and have taken part in numerous runs organised by Bupa, including the Great North Run. I also go cycling with my father most weekends along a section of a Coast to Coast route - we've even done a few weekends in Hamsterley forest.

I am a member of the Newcastle Climbing Centre, where I've taken an introductory climbing course, where I learnt the basics needed to climb unsupervised in the centre; safety procedures, knots and belaying.

I often research what new technologies and services are available, which can include the creation of prototypes to better clarify or prove particular concepts. This aids in trying to keep my skills fresh and up-to-date. This also has the added benefit of giving a greater understanding when it comes to planning and estimating future projects.